Luis Alvaro Leon Ramirez

leon9326@gmail.com Cel: +57 316 8299432

Career Summary

System Engineer who works as a Java Developer, He has more than six years of experience as a Software Developer using Java (Spring Framework) like programming language, He also has knowledge about other technologies like Kotlin (Backend), BPM(IBM), Camunda and some services from AWS (lambda, Dynamo, Api gateway, cloud watch). He has worked in different projects following SCRUM agile methodology.

Summary of Qualifications

Skills:

- Java 8/11
- Spring
 Framework
- JUnit
- Swagger
- Mockito
- REST Service
- Design Patterns
- Rest Api

- Microservices
- Maven
- Kotlin

- Kotest (MockK)
- OOP

Languages:

• Spanish (native speaker)

• English (B2)

Career History:

FORTE GROUP, CALI Colombia

November 2021- Currently

Positions:

Senior Java Software Developer

- Development of micro services using Java SpringBoot
- Unit testing Mockito.
- Software Development following agile SCRUM methodology.
- Participate in new features definition
- Cooperate with QA team, test functionality
- Integrate Camunda workflows with Java for business requirements

GLOBANT, CALI, Colombia

Oct. 2020 - November 2021

Positions:

Java Software Designer

Oct. 2020 - Currently

- Java Developer Lead who works on projects with teams all over the world.
- Development of micro services using Java in AWS like cloud platform (Spring Boot, Spring cloud, Spring config, Hystrix ,Eureka, Ribon, Feign, JUnit, Mockito)
- Development of micro services using Kotlin (Spring Boot, Spring cloud, Spring config, Kotest, MockK)
- Responsible for the communication between developer team and architect.
- Ensure the correct implementation of the technical definitions designed by the architect.
- Software Development following agile SCRUM methodology.
- Consume SOAP and REST services.
- Make the estimation and development of new requirements
- Make the unit tests of the developed requirements into Java applications (Junit, Mockito, Spring Boot Test).
- Make the unit tests of the developed requirements into Kotlin applications (Kotest, Spock)
- Make diagnostics and solutions about production incidents.

PRAGMA, CALI, Colombia

Jun. 2016 – Oct. 2020

Positions:

Java Technical Lead

Sept. 2019 - Oct. 2020

- Java Technical Lead in charge the team, with the responsibility to define integration mechanisms in Java technologies and AWS like cloud platform and following SCRUM agile methodology
- Development of micro services using Java (Spring Boot) Hystrix ,Eureka, Ribon and Feign in AWS like platform
- Responsible for the communication between developer team and architect.
- Responsible for defining the backend user history of the project.
- Ensure the correct implementation of the technical definitions designed by the architect.
- Development of lambda in AWS with Node Js and Java, using serverless framework.
- Mediation of SOAP to REST services using Java.
- Software Development following agile SCRUM methodology.
- Consume SOAP and REST services.
- Responsible for definition, documentation and communication of technical decisions according to the customer needs along the vital cycle of the development.
- Make the estimation and development of new requirements
- Make the unit tests of the developed requirements into Java applications (Junit, Mockito, Spring Boot Test).
- Give support to the activities of internal tests and final user tests about applications.
- Make diagnostics and solutions about production incidents.

Java Developer

Jun. 2016 - Sept. 2019

- Development of REST services to mediate information of financial entities using Java (Spring).
- Development of micro services using Java (Spring Boot)
- Development of applications using Java (Spring MVC)
- Mediation of SOAP to REST services using Java.
- Full Stack Software Developer Java/Angular.
- Development of reports in Java using jasper Reports.
- Software Development following agile SCRUM methodology.
- Make the unit tests of the developed requirements into Java applications (Junit, Mockito)

Education

Institución Universitaria Antonio José Camacho, Cali, Colombia Systems Engineer

Jan. 2013 - Dec. 2018

Personal Information

Full Name: Luis Alvaro Leon Ramirez

Email: leon9326@gmail.com

Contact Number: +57 3168299432

Location: Cali, Colombia.

Personal References

Esteban Duran cel: 319 5759098Camilo Hurtado cel: 311 7737625